Bruno Martins

Junior Software Developer | Lab Technician

Location: Barcelos, Portugal Phone: +351 962 915 768 Email: bruno@kazy.pt linkedin.com/in/bmrtins Website: kazy.pt

PROFILE

Junior software developer with 5+ years of laboratory experience using self-developed tools to perform automated data processing and analysis. Developed apps using **Python** to automate repeatable everyday tasks as well as work-related apps to improve productivity. Passionate about learning new programming languages and related technologies and developing responsive frontend web apps using **React** and **CSS**.

Fast learner and highly-motivated in multidisciplinary environments with both team-oriented and individual tasks.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Laboratory Technician, Matias & Araújo, S.A. • Barcelos, Nov. 2020 — Present

- Data input on **Tecnorama** automatic dye dispensing system.
- System maintenance and troubleshooting.
- Software automation improvements using Python.

Laboratory Assistant (Part time), Microbiology Department, UTAD • Vila Real, Sep. 2018 — Jul. 2020 **Intern Laboratory Technician**, Cytogenetics Laboratory, CHTMAD • Vila Real, 2017

Golf Course Marshal, Pestana Golf Resort • Carvoeiro, 2015 — 2019

EDUCATION

Master's degree in Biochemistry • UTAD, Set. 2021

Bachelor's degree in Biochemistry • UTAD, Jul. 2018

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

React (incl. Hooks, Context, Routes), JavaScript (incl. Async), HTML 5, CSS 3 (incl. Flexbox, Grid), Firebase (incl. Cloud Firestore, Auth), Python, Git

CERTIFICATES

Build Web Apps with React & Firebase by Shaun Pelling • Udemy, May 2023

Build Responsive Real-World Websites with HTML and CSS by Jonas Schmedtmann • Udemy, Mar. 2023

Modern JavaScript (Complete guide, from Novice to Ninja) by Shaun Pelling • Udemy, Nov. 2022

LANGUAGES

Portuguese (native), English (excellent), Spanish (intermediate)

OTHERS

XIII ENEBIOQ Organizing Committee – Head of Publishing Department • Vila Real, Jul./Aug. 2021

Event's website development.